# Global settings for the linux-lab Helm chart
name: linux-user-management-lab
namespace: labs

# Autoscaling settings
autoscaling:
  enabled: false

# Deployment settings
replicaCount: 1

appLabels:
  app: "devopclinics-lab"
  instance: "linux-user-management"


# Image settings
image:
  repository: dclinics/linux-labs
  tag: "latest"
  pullPolicy: IfNotPresent

# Service settings
service:
  name: linux-user-lab-service
  type: NodePort
  port: 5000           # The port on which your app listens
  targetPort: 5000     # The port in the container
  nodePort: 30001  

# Annotations and labels for the pods
podAnnotations: {}
podLabels: {}

# Image pull secrets
imagePullSecrets: []

# Security context for the pod and container
podSecurityContext: {}
securityContext: {}

# Probes for liveness and readiness
livenessProbe:
  httpGet:
    path: /
    port: 5000
  initialDelaySeconds: 5
  timeoutSeconds: 5
readinessProbe:
  httpGet:
    path: /
    port: 5000
  initialDelaySeconds: 5
  timeoutSeconds: 5

# Resource requests and limits
resources: {}

# Volume mounts and volumes
volumeMounts:
  - name: questions-volume
    mountPath: /app/config
volumes:
  - name: questions-volume
    configMap:
      name: linux-user-management-questions

# Node selector, affinity, and tolerations
nodeSelector: {}
affinity: {}
tolerations: {}

selector:
  app.kubernetes.io/name: devopclinics-lab
  app.kubernetes.io/instance: linux-user-management

# Ingress settings
ingress:
  enabled: false
  hosts: []
  tls: false


# ConfigMap data specific to the service
configData:
  configMapName: "linux-user-management-devopclinics-lab-questions"
  config:
    title: "Linux User Management lab"
  questions: 
    - question: "Create a new user named 'developer'."
      answer: "sudo useradd developer"
    - question: "Set the password for the user 'developer' to 'password123'."
      answer: "sudo passwd developer"
    - question: "Create a new group called 'adminteam'."
      answer: "sudo groupadd adminteam"
    - question: "Add the user 'developer' to the 'adminteam' group."
      answer: "sudo usermod -aG adminteam developer"
    - question: "Delete the user 'developer' and remove their home directory."
      answer: "sudo userdel -r developer"
    - question: "Create a new user named 'tester' with a home directory at '/home/tester'."
      answer: "sudo useradd -m -d /home/tester tester"
    - question: "Set the shell for the user 'tester' to '/bin/bash'."
      answer: "sudo usermod -s /bin/bash tester"
    - question: "Lock the user 'tester' to prevent them from logging in."
      answer: "sudo usermod -L tester"
    - question: "Unlock the user 'tester' so they can log in again."
      answer: "sudo usermod -U tester"
    - question: "Change the primary group of the user 'tester' to 'adminteam'."
      answer: "sudo usermod -g adminteam tester"
    - question: "Create a new group named 'developers'."
      answer: "sudo groupadd developers"
    - question: "Add the user 'tester' to the 'developers' group."
      answer: "sudo usermod -aG developers tester"
    - question: "Remove the user 'tester' from the 'developers' group."
      answer: "sudo gpasswd -d tester developers"
    - question: "Set an expiration date of '2024-12-31' for the user 'tester'."
      answer: "sudo chage -E 2024-12-31 tester"
    - question: "Check the password aging information for the user 'tester'."
      answer: "sudo chage -l tester"
    - question: "Create a new user named 'auditor' without a home directory."
      answer: "sudo useradd -M auditor"
    - question: "Force the user 'tester' to change their password at the next login."
      answer: "sudo passwd --expire tester"
    - question: "Change the user ID (UID) of 'tester' to '1500'."
      answer: "sudo usermod -u 1500 tester"
    - question: "Change the group ID (GID) of the 'developers' group to '1600'."
      answer: "sudo groupmod -g 1600 developers"
    - question: "Remove the 'developers' group from the system."
      answer: "sudo groupdel developers"
    - question: "Create a new system user named 'backupuser' with no login shell."
      answer: "sudo useradd -r -s /usr/sbin/nologin backupuser"
    - question: "Set the user 'developer' to have read, write, and execute permissions on their home directory, but only read and execute permissions for the group and others."
      answer: "sudo chmod 755 /home/developer"
    - question: "Change the ownership of the '/var/www' directory to the user 'developer' and the group 'adminteam'."
      answer: "sudo chown developer:adminteam /var/www"
    - question: "Create a new user named 'dataprocessor' with a specific UID of 2001."
      answer: "sudo useradd -u 2001 dataprocessor"
    - question: "Add a comment 'Database Administrator' to the user 'dbadmin'."
      answer: "sudo usermod -c 'Database Administrator' dbadmin"